<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<data>
    <cocktail name="Appletini">
        <prime>vodka</prime>
        <description>
            An apple martini (appletini for short) is a cocktail containing vodka and one or more of apple juice, apple cider, apple liqueur, or apple brandy.
            Optionally, vermouth may be included, as in a regular martini.
            Typically, the apple vodka is shaken or stirred with a sweet and sour mix and then strained into a cocktail glass.
            The appletini is a variation of the vodka martini, which diverges in taste from the typical dry martini by adding apple juice and/or apple liqueur, or apple schnapps.
            It tends to be served in the standard martini glass, but truly differs from the martini in taste, since it is a fruity tasting drink with the apple flavor usually masking the vodka.
        </description>
        <history></history>
        <trivia>
            This drink, properly called an Adam's Apple Martini, was created and popularized in 1997 by Adam Karsten, a bartender at Lola's in West Hollywood, California.
            The appletini is the favorite alcoholic drink of John "J.D." Dorian in the sitcom Scrubs in which it is often characterized as being somewhat effeminate.
            Along with a rum and diet coke, it is also the favorite drink of Alan Harper from Two and a Half Men.
            In the 2010 film The Social Network, in the initial meeting between Facebook co-founders Mark Zuckerberg and Eduardo Saverin and Napster co-founder Sean Parker, Parker buys the table a few rounds of the drink.
            In real life, Zuckerberg never had an appletini until he attended the film's premiere.
            After seeing the film, Zuckerberg made the appletini Facebook's official drink.
        </trivia>
        <comments>
            The appletini was anything but bright green, instead it was a very light sage green.
            I love Granny Smith apples and this tastes like that. Nice clean apple flavor.
            If you love the apple flavored jolly rancher and the smell than this is the juice you should get.
            I keep thinking I am eating green apple jolly rancher it is amazing.
            If you love fruit and want to taste apple, this is the one for you!
            This juice has a nice apple flavor, but not overwhelming with just a hint of vodka.
            Tastes like a nice, fresh green apple right out of the fridge.
            There's no noticeable tartness to this.
            If you are looking for a crisp, refreshing, sweet and slightly tangy apple flavor -- look no further.
        </comments>
        <ingredients>
            INGREDIENTS:
            40ml (3 parts) Vodka,
            15ml (1 part) Apple schnapps / Calvados,
            15ml (1 part) Cointreau.
        </ingredients>
        <mixing>
            MIXING:
            Mix in a shaker, then pour into a chilled glass.
            Garnish and serve.
        </mixing>
    </cocktail>
    <cocktail name="Pina Colada">
        <prime>rum</prime>
        <description>
            is a sweet cocktail made with rum, cream of coconut, and pineapple juice, usually served either blended or shaken with ice. It may be garnished with a pineapple wedge, a maraschino cherry, or both.
            You don't have to go to the tropics to enjoy a smooth, sweet coconut flavor.
            Instead, you can enjoy it from the comfort of your own home with our Pina Colada flavor.
            Just like your favorite tropical beverage, the Pina Colada has a smooth, rather subdued taste, making it perfect for everyday use.
        </description>
        <history>
            The Pina Colada has roots that can be traced to Puerto Rico and has long been considered the island Country's national drink. The cocktail was said to be invented by a bartender at the luxurious Caribe Hilton Hotel's Beachcomber Bar in 1952 shortly after a key ingredient, Coco Lopez cream of coconut, was developed. Puerto Rico honors the cocktail with a National Pina Colada Day that is celebrated each year on July 10th.
            Created byRamon "Monchito" Marrero, Beachcomber Bar, Caribe Hilton, San Juan, Puerto Rico.
            Year 1954
        </history>
        <trivia>
            The name pina colada literally means "strained pineapple", a reference to the freshly pressed and strained pineapple juice used in the drink's preparation.
            The earliest known story states that in the 19th century, Puerto Rican pirate Roberto Cofresí, to boost his crew's morale, gave them a beverage or cocktail that contained coconut, pineapple and white rum.
            This was what would be later known as the famous pina colada.
            With his death in 1825, the recipe for the pina colada was lost.
            The pina colada has been the national drink of Puerto Rico since 1978.
        </trivia>
        <comments>
            classic tropical cocktail with rum, pineapple and coconut milk.
            This classic recipe will transport you to paradise.
            What I have in mind is the sort of weekend where you go to a nice, exotic location — preferably one with a beach — and relax with a tall, cool, refreshing drink (and forget about the rest of the world).
            Although the rum adds a wonderful subflavor to this drink, it's really the flavors of the pineapple and coconut cream that dominate.
            Often when we're on vacation (at some exotic destination or on a cruise)
            Must be because it's so pretty and such a smooth drink.
            makes me want to go the beach hang out and enjoy one right now.
            Ooh yummy I love pina coladas during the summer by the pool!
            I'm ready for a tropical vacation! Or maybe just a pina colada on a relaxing evening at home. :)
            I think I need to make this and bring back those happy memories of fun and sun
            Haha I wasn't aware it's quite high calorie though.
            this is kind of a caloric drink
        </comments>
        <ingredients>
            INGREDIENTS:
            3 cl (one part) white rum,
            3 cl (one part) coconut milk,
            9 cl (3 parts) pineapple juice.
        </ingredients>
        <mixing>
            MIXING:
            Put all ingredients into an electric blender with 2 cups of crushed ice.
            Blend at a high speed for a short length of time.
            Strain into a collins glass and serve with a straw.
        </mixing>
    </cocktail>
    <cocktail name="Long Island Iced Tea">
        <prime>tequila, gin, rum, vodka, triple sec</prime>
        <description>
            A Long Island Iced Tea is a type of alcoholic mixed drink typically made with, among other ingredients, tequila, vodka, light rum, triple sec, and gin.
            It is so named because of the resemblance to the color and taste of iced tea.
            A popular version mixes equal parts vodka, gin, tequila, rum, and triple sec with 1.5 parts sour mix and a splash of cola, which gives the drink the same amber hue as its namesake.
            Most variants use equal parts of the main liquors, but include a smaller amount of triple sec (or other orange-flavored liqueur).
            Close variants often replace the sour mix with lemon juice, replace the cola with diet cola or actual iced tea, or add white crème de menthe; however, most variants do not include any tea.
        </description>
        <history>
            There is some dispute as to the origin of the Long Island Iced Tea.
            However, numerous sources attribute the origin to one or both of two inventors in the 1920s or 1970s.
            The Long Island Iced Tea appears in literature as early as 1961.
            Robert "Rosebud" Butt claims to have invented the drink as an entry in a contest to create a new mixed drink including Triple Sec, in 1972 while he worked at the Oak Beach Inn on Long Island, NY.
            Various local New York references echo Butt's claims.
            Local rumors also ascribe the origin to either Butt or another bartender at the Oak Beach Inn, Chris Bendicksen.
        </history>
        <trivia>
            Some restaurants substitute brandy for the tequila.
            Some variants of the drink have alternative names such as Texas Iced Tea, Georgia Iced Tea, Tokyo Tea, Three Mile Island, and Adios Mother Fucker.
            The drink has a much higher alcohol concentration (approximately 22 percent) than most highball drinks due to the relatively small amount of mixer. Long islands can be ordered "extra long", which further increases the alcohol to mixer ratio.
        </trivia>
        <comments>
            Most Long Island Iced Teas contain over two-ounces of mixed spirits, making them relatively potent drink.
            Although half-ounce liquor portions may seem small, they have a significant cumulative affect.
            It's a stealth drink.
            It goes down so easy, the high alcohol content sneaks up on you.
            It's also a great pre-mixer to make in pitchers and serve at parties.
            Summertime is an ideal time to serve the Long Island Iced Tea, because its taste is reminiscent of iced tea even though there's no tea in it at all.
            The drink also shares a similar taste to tea.
            i think it tastes like artificially sweetened tea beverage ie: nestea or something like that
            it tastes like very sweet ice tea made from a mix served in cheap bars and diners
            taste like non-alcoholic iced tea
        </comments>
        <ingredients>
            INGREDIENTS:
            1.5 cl Tequila,
            1.5 cl Vodka,
            1.5 cl White rum,
            1.5 cl Triple sec,
            1.5 cl Gin,
            2.5 cl Lemon juice,
            3.0 cl Gomme Syrup,
            1 dash of Cola.
        </ingredients>
        <mixing>
            MIXING:
            Mix ingredients together over ice in a glass.
            Pour into shaker and give ONE brisk shake.
            Pour back into glass and make sure there is a touch of fizz at the top.
            Garnish with lemon.
        </mixing>
    </cocktail>
    <cocktail name="Californication">
        <prime>vodka, gin, rum, tequila</prime>
        <description>
            Not to be outdone, California has put its own twist on the Long Island Iced Tea with the creation of the Californication, the golden state variation of the popular Long Island cocktail.
            The Californication is a mixture of rum, vodka, tequila and gin finished with orange liqueur, lemon juice and orange juice to taste.
            Strong but sweet.
            The mixed drink is finished with either a piece of orange or a twisted peel of orange rind.
            The Californication is not a subtle cocktail, but the citrus flavor imparted by the orange liqueur and orange juice attempt to disguise the punch it packs from the mixture of spirits.
            The name of the cocktail, Californication, is based on a term that is prominent in the lyrics of a song by the rock group, the Red Hot Chili Peppers.
            There has also been a television series that has run since August 2007 with the same name.
        </description>
        <history></history>
        <trivia></trivia>
        <comments></comments>
        <ingredients>
            INGREDIENTS:
            15ml each vodka, gin, white rum and tequila,
            15ml freshly squeezed lemon juice,
            about 70ml orange juice.
        </ingredients>
        <mixing>
            MIXING:
            Stir in a large glass and top up with use.
        </mixing>
    </cocktail>
    <cocktail name="Pina Colada">
        <prime>rum</prime>
        <description>
            is a sweet cocktail made with rum, cream of coconut, and pineapple juice, usually served either blended or shaken with ice. It may be garnished with a pineapple wedge, a maraschino cherry, or both.
            You don't have to go to the tropics to enjoy a smooth, sweet coconut flavor.
            Instead, you can enjoy it from the comfort of your own home with our Pina Colada flavor.
            Just like your favorite tropical beverage, the Pina Colada has a smooth, rather subdued taste, making it perfect for everyday use.
            Haha I wasn't aware it's quite high calorie though.
            this is kind of a caloric drink
        </description>
        <history>
            The Pina Colada has roots that can be traced to Puerto Rico and has long been considered the island Country's national drink. The cocktail was said to be invented by a bartender at the luxurious Caribe Hilton Hotel's Beachcomber Bar in 1952 shortly after a key ingredient, Coco Lopez cream of coconut, was developed. Puerto Rico honors the cocktail with a National Pina Colada Day that is celebrated each year on July 10th.
            Created byRamon "Monchito" Marrero, Beachcomber Bar, Caribe Hilton, San Juan, Puerto Rico.
            Year 1954
        </history>
        <trivia>
            The name pina colada literally means "strained pineapple", a reference to the freshly pressed and strained pineapple juice used in the drink's preparation.
            The earliest known story states that in the 19th century, Puerto Rican pirate Roberto Cofresí, to boost his crew's morale, gave them a beverage or cocktail that contained coconut, pineapple and white rum.
            This was what would be later known as the famous pina colada.
            With his death in 1825, the recipe for the pina colada was lost.
            The pina colada has been the national drink of Puerto Rico since 1978.
        </trivia>
        <comments>
            classic tropical cocktail with rum, pineapple and coconut milk.
            This classic recipe will transport you to paradise.
            What I have in mind is the sort of weekend where you go to a nice, exotic location — preferably one with a beach — and relax with a tall, cool, refreshing drink (and forget about the rest of the world).
            Although the rum adds a wonderful subflavor to this drink, it's really the flavors of the pineapple and coconut cream that dominate.
            Often when we're on vacation (at some exotic destination or on a cruise)
            Must be because it's so pretty and such a smooth drink.
            makes me want to go the beach hang out and enjoy one right now.
            Ooh yummy I love pina coladas during the summer by the pool!
            I'm ready for a tropical vacation! Or maybe just a pina colada on a relaxing evening at home. :)
            I think I need to make this and bring back those happy memories of fun and sun
        </comments>
        <ingredients>
            INGREDIENTS:
            3 cl (one part) white rum,
            3 cl (one part) coconut milk,
            9 cl (3 parts) pineapple juice.
        </ingredients>
        <mixing>
            MIXING:
            Put all ingredients into an electric blender with 2 cups of crushed ice.
            Blend at a high speed for a short length of time.
            Strain into a collins glass and serve with a straw.
        </mixing>
    </cocktail>
    <cocktail name="Margarita">
        <prime>tequila</prime>
        <description>
            The Margarita gets lots of love in the US. Partly that's because of its slightly sour — but wonderful and refreshing — lime taste.
            And partly it's because the drink has become synonymous with a carefree, easy-going lifestyle.
            The drink is served shaken with ice (on the rocks), blended with ice (frozen margarita), or without ice (straight up). Although it has become acceptable to serve a margarita in a wide variety of glass types, ranging from cocktail and wine glasses to pint glasses and even large schooners, the drink is traditionally served in the eponymous margarita glass, a stepped-diameter variant of a cocktail glass or champagne coupe somewhat resembling an inverted sombrero.
        </description>
        <history>
            One of the earliest stories is of the margarita being invented in 1938 by Carlos "Danny" Herrera at his restaurant Rancho La Gloria, halfway between Tijuana and Rosarito, Mexico, created for customer and former Ziegfeld dancer Marjorie King, who was allergic to many spirits, but not to tequila.
            A commonly accepted origin story of the Margarita is that it was invented in October 1941, at Hussong's Cantina in Ensenada, Mexico, by bartender Don Carlos Orozco.
            One afternoon, Margarita Henkel, the daughter of the then German ambassador visited the cantina and Don Carlos who had been experimenting with drinks offered her one.
            The cocktail consisted of equal parts of tequila, Mexican orange liqueur called Controy (A.K.A. Naranja in the United States), and lime, shaken and served over ice in a salt-rimmed glass.
            As she was the first to try the drink, Don Carlos decided to name it after her and the "Margarita" was born.
            A little additional sweetness helps to balance out the recipe and bridges the gap between classic and lime slushy.
        </history>
        <trivia>
            You know, as in Jimmy Buffett's song, Margaritaville.
            The most important ingredient for this drink is tequila.
            You want to use something decent, but not overly fancy.
            a cocktail consisting of tequila, triple sec (such as Cointreau) and lime or lemon juice, often served with salt on the rim of the glass.
            But one thing is clear: the Margarita is basically a "sour," like the Whiskey Sour, the Sidecar, and the Classic Daiquiri. All these drinks are made with liquor + citrus (lemon or lime) + something sweet to temper the sourness of the citrus (simple syrup or triple sec).
            I find it works better with the lime's tartness and gives a smoothness to the Margarita.
        </trivia>
        <comments>
            The simplest example is the balance of sweet and sour.
            Since it's such a well known, and simple, cocktail you'd think getting a decent Margarita would be easy.
            The Margarita recipe is one of the easier cocktail recipes, and can be considered a "base cocktail".
            Traditional margaritas are served over ice with a salty rim, but some people like them frozen, it gives it a slightly sweeter, less potent taste.
            They are sweet and tangy.
            A traditional margarita is made with lime juice and is sweetened, often with sour mix.
            Tequila is the alcohol and it does have a very strong taste.
            It's salty and super yummy!
            One of the properties of crystalline fructose is that it causes a cooling sensation on the tongue when the crystals melt.
            Fresh squeezed lime juice is a must, period, end of story. Unless you commit to that, you'll never be able to produce a truly great Margarita.
            The Margarita is about balance, and should not taste like a "salt lick" found on a farm.
            If you still find that too salty, try mixing it with a bit of sugar or, better yet, fructose.
            Just another level of refreshing.
        </comments>
        <ingredients>
            INGREDIENTS:
            3.5 cL (7 parts) tequila,
            2 cL (4 parts) Cointreau,
            1.5 cL (3 parts) lime juice.
        </ingredients>
        <mixing>
            MIXING:
            Rub rim of cocktail glass with lime juice, dip rim in salt.
            Shake all ingredients with ice, strain into the salt-rimmed glass, and serve.
        </mixing>
    </cocktail>
    <cocktail name="Caipirinha">
        <prime>cachaca</prime>
        <description>
            is Brazil's national cocktail, made with cachaca (sugar cane hard liquor), sugar and lime.
            Cachaca is Brazil's most common distilled alcoholic beverage (also known as Pinga or Caninha).
            Although both rum and cachaca are made from sugarcane derived products, specifically in cachaca, the alcohol results from the fermentation of fresh sugarcane juice that is afterwards distilled, while rum is usually made from by-products from refineries, such as molasses.
        </description>
        <history>
            Although the real origin of caipirinha as we know it today is unknown, according to one account it began around 1918 in the state of Sao Paulo with a popular recipe made with lime, garlic and honey, indicated for patients with the Spanish flu.
            As it was quite common to add some distilled spirits to home remedies in order to expedite the therapeutic effect, rum was commonly used.
            Until one day someone decided to remove the garlic and honey.
        </history>
        <trivia>
            The caipirinha is the strongest national cocktail of Brazil, and is imbibed in restaurants, bars, and many households throughout the country.
            Once almost unknown outside Brazil, the drink has become more popular and more widely available in recent years, in large part due to the rising availability of first-rate brands of cachaca outside Brazil.
            The word caipirinha is the diminutive version of the word caipira, which refers to someone from the countryside, being an almost exact equivalent of the American English hillbilly or the Lowland Scots teuchter.
            The word may be used as either a masculine or a feminine noun, but when referring to this drink it is only feminine (usage of diminutives is common in Brazil).
            In the Brazilian vocabulary, the word caipirinha is mostly associated with the drink itself rather than the class of person.
        </trivia>
        <comments>
            imagine a cross between a Mojito and a Classic Daiquiri, though with a bit more presence.
            If you want to make a Caipirinha, you'll need to buy some cachaca.
            Cachaca is made from cane sugar.
            Making this cocktail requires muddling sugar with lime wedges.
            Balancing the amount of sugar in this drink is tricky.
            Cachaca has a sweetish (almost fruity) and herbal flavor with a slight aftertaste that reminds me a bit of tequila.
            It's a tad harsh, so I wouldn't want to drink the white version neat or on the rocks
            The Caipirinha takes quite well to experimentation, so it's a drink you can play with a bit.
            So feel free to add more lime if you find that the amount specified in the recipe isn't sufficient.
            Some people say raw sugar is traditional in this drink, while others insist on white cane sugar.
            this drink is pretty close in spirit to the Mojito - you could even add mint to it, if you wanted
            We drink caipis here (buenos aires) like it's the end of the world.
            This does look like a very summery drink but it sure is difficult to pronounce and spell.
            I have memories popping up of drinking this on a holiday in Brazil some years ago, and I do remember it being quite addictive.
            I usually use ice cubes, but crushed ice is great in this drink, too.
            And you're right that it's so wonderful for summer!
            Sweet and citrus... I'm thirsty!
            What a simple little drink and I love the touch of sweetness.
            Would love to be sipping on one right now.
            well, maybe 2 sips. ;-) Great tasting drink, though.
        </comments>
        <ingredients>
            INGREDIENTS:
            5 cl cachaca,
            Half a lime cut into 4 wedges,
            2 teaspoons white sugar.
        </ingredients>
        <mixing>
            MIXING:
            The drink is prepared by smashing the fruit and the sugar together, and adding the liquor.
            This can be made into a single glass, usually large, that can be shared amongst people, or into a larger jar, from where it is served in individual glasses.
        </mixing>
    </cocktail>
    <cocktail name="Mint Julep">
        <prime>whiskey</prime>
        <description>
            The mint julep is a mixed alcoholic drink, or cocktail, consisting primarily of bourbon (or some other spirit), water, crushed or shaved ice, and fresh mint.
            As a bourbon-based cocktail, it is associated with the American South and the cuisine of the Southern United States in general, and the Kentucky Derby in particular.
            The Kentucky Derby is among the most famous horse races in the US (and part of the Triple Crown Series that also includes the Preakness Stakes and the Belmont Stakes).
            Traditionally held the first Saturday in May, it's the first big US race of the season.
            This ice cold cocktail traditionally is served in a silver cup — which the imbiber holds by the bottom and top edges in order not to disturb the frosty coating of condensation that develops on the outside.
        </description>
        <history>
            The origins of the mint julep are clouded and may never be definitively known.
            It originated in the southern United States, probably during the eighteenth century.
            U.S. Senator Henry Clay of Kentucky introduced the drink to Washington, D.C., at the Round Robin Bar in the famous Willard Hotel during his residence in the city.
            The term "julep" is generally defined as a sweet drink, particularly one used as a vehicle for medicine.
            The word itself is derived from the Persian word Golab, meaning rose water.
        </history>
        <trivia>
            Well, usually we muddle mint at the bottom of the serving glass (typically with some sugar) before adding ice and liquor.  Doing so releases the mint's volatile oils, and thus helps flavor the drink.
            We tend to associate whiskey (specifically bourbon) with juleps, but you can use any liquor.
            Most recipes for Mint Juleps include a lot of booze — typically 3 or 4 ounces of bourbon.
            Consider making mint-flavored simple syrup for this drink — you'll get much more mint flavor than the standard recipe produces.
        </trivia>
        <comments>
            Add a good handful of mint and stir frequently until the mixture just comes to a simmer.
            Granulated sugar that fails to dissolve completely can make drinks somewhat gritty.
            The idea is that you'll poke your nose into the garnish as you sip your drink, which allows you to inhale some of the mint aroma.
            In fact, they probably weren't made that way until the late 1700s (when bourbon became known as, well, bourbon).
            Before that time, rum (dark) was probably the spirit of choice, although Regan reports that both peach brandy and regular brandy were common in early forms of the drink.
            Mint Juleps are a natural when warm weather arrives, so it's not surprising that they have become linked to late-spring and summer events.
            Spring is a good time for horse racing carnival.
            Hi Sue, the frosted silver mugs do look pretty.
            I want mine in a silver cup.
            And to think I am always pulling spearmint to stop it from taking over my garden!
            the dominating flavor is bourbon, sweetness next (from the sugar), and mint last.
            On the day of the race I had to order a mint Julep
        </comments>
        <ingredients>
            INGREDIENTS:
            6 cL Bourbon whiskey,
            4 mint leaves,
            1 teaspoon powdered sugar,
            2 teaspoons water.
        </ingredients>
        <mixing>
            MIXING:
            In a highball glass gently muddle the mint, sugar and water.
            Fill the glass with cracked ice, add Bourbon and stir well until the glass is well frosted.
            Garnish with a mint sprig.
        </mixing>
    </cocktail>
    <cocktail name="Mai Tai">
        <prime>rum</prime>
        <description>
            The Mai Tai is an alcoholic cocktail based on rum, Curacao liqueur, and lime juice, associated with Polynesian-style settings.
            The Mai Tai is perfect as a summer cocktail: sultry, yet cooling and refreshing at the same time.
            So, lest you harbor suspicions about the Mai Tai because of its parasol persuasion, let me hasten to add that this is arguably one of the world's top ten drinks.
            A real Mai Tai contains just a few ingredients.
            But ingredient quality is important in this drink, so choosing the proper ones is an important consideration, as we'll discuss in the notes.
        </description>
        <history>
            It is said to have been invented by the proprietor of Trader Vic's of Oakland, California in 1944.
            He created the drink for some friends who were visiting from Tahiti and after one of them exclaimed that the drink was "Maita'i", or very good in Tahitian, the name stuck.
            A rival restaurant, Don the Beachcomber, also claims to have invented the cocktail in 1933 with a more complex version of the drink.
            The truth probably lies somewhere in between, but California was more than likely the birthplace of the popular cocktail.
        </history>
        <trivia>
            It's impossible to duplicate Trader Vic's original Mai Tai because he used 17-year-old Wray &amp; Nephew rum, which is no longer available.
            The Mai Tai was also prominently featured in the Elvis Presley film Blue Hawaii.
            Today, the Mai Tai is synonymous with Tiki culture both past and present.
            Richard M. Nixon also hit his high point in the 1950's and 60's, and then disappeared (so to speak) during the 70's. So it's fitting that the Mai Tai was his favorite cocktail.
        </trivia>
        <comments>
            The umbrella is optional, but a cocktail straw makes it more enjoyable.
            The higher quality the rum, the better this drink tastes.
            Jamaican rums are ideal in a Mai Tai.
            The Mai Tai requires Orgeat syrup, a sweet syrup flavored with almonds and orange or rose water.
            World's Best Umbrella Drink
            Speaking of straws, that's the one garnish I think is necessary to this drink.
            Common garnishes for the Mai Tai include lime wedges, an empty lime shell half (just chuck it into the glass for a nice spot of color), pineapple wedges, maraschino cherries, mint sprigs — and of course umbrellas.
            And if you happen to have some tiki mugs lurking somewhere in your cupboard — well, haul them out to serve this drink.
            Cowabunga, dude.
        </comments>
        <ingredients>
            INGREDIENTS:
            4 cl (8 parts) white rum,
            2 cl (4 parts) dark rum,
            1.5 cl (3 parts) orange curacao,
            1.5 cl (3 parts) Orgeat syrup,
            1 cl (2 parts) fresh lime juice.
        </ingredients>
        <mixing>
            MIXING:
            Shake all ingredients with ice.
            Strain into glass.
            Garnish and serve with straw.
        </mixing>
    </cocktail>
    <cocktail name="Mojito">
        <prime>rum</prime>
        <description>
            Mojito is a traditional Cuban highball.
            This refreshing cocktail packs a lot of flavor and pleasure into each tall, cool glass.
            So it makes an excellent thirst quencher for a long, hot summer afternoon.
            You can have two — and still keep your wits about you.
            Traditionally, a mojito is a cocktail that consists of five ingredients: white rum, sugar (traditionally sugar cane juice), lime juice, sparkling water, and mint.
            The original Cuban recipe uses spearmint or yerba buena, a mint variety very popular on the island.
            Its combination of sweetness, refreshing citrus, and mint flavors is intended to complement the potent kick of the rum, and has made this clear highball a popular summer drink.
            The cocktail has a relatively low alcohol content (about 10 percent alcohol by volume).
        </description>
        <history>
            Havana is the birthplace of the Mojito, although the exact origin of this classic cocktail is the subject of debate.
            One story traces the Mojito to a similar 16th century drink known as "El Draque", after Francis Drake.
            In 1586, after his successful raid at Cartagena de Indias Drake's ships sailed towards Havana but there was an epidemic of dysentery and scurvy on board.
            It was known that the local South American Indians had remedies for various tropical illnesses; so a small boarding party went ashore on Cuba and came back with ingredients for a medicine which was effective.
            The ingredients were aguardiente de cana (a crude form of rum, translates as fire water from sugar cane) added with local tropical ingredients; lime, sugarcane juice and mint.
            Drinking lime juice in itself would have been a great help in staving off scurvy and dysentery.
            Tafia / Rum was used as soon as it became widely available to the British (ca. 1650).
            While this drink was not called a Mojito at this time, it was still the original combination of these ingredients.
            Several other stories exist regarding the cocktail's true origins, but most stories simply provide evidence to how long the general recipe has been in existence. The great author, Ernest Hemingway, was known to have developed quite a taste for the refreshing drink.
        </history>
        <trivia>
            Ernest Hemingway, who spent much time in Cuba, liked Mojitos.
        </trivia>
        <comments>
            It's also exceptionally easy to make.
            Traditionally, you make this drink in a glass.
            That is, you add all the ingredients to the glass and stir them with a spoon
            For this drink, you should use a tall glass that holds 10 to 14 ounces (12 is ideal).
            This recipe yields one drink, and takes about 5 minutes to prepare.
            It's easy to scale up if you're serving thirsty hordes.
            Some people like to add the empty shell of a lime half (one that you squeezed for juice) to the bottom of the glass as additional garnish.
            Gorgeous day, sitting in the sand outside a beach hut bar on the Bay of Pigs and the barman asks if I'd like a mojito.
            I drank that one and several more and then went back to Havana and had a few more and by then I was hooked.
            We love the fresh, clean flavor.
            Lime, rum, and sugar.
            this drink is more refreshing than thirst quenching
            The Mojito is a fantastic drink if you are undecided when ordering something from the bar.
            When preparing a mojito, lime juice is added to sugar (or syrup) and mint leaves.
            The mixture is then gently mashed with a muddler.
            The mint leaves should only be bruised to release the essential oils and should not be shredded.
            Then rum is added and the mixture is briefly stirred to dissolve the sugar and to lift the mint leaves up from the bottom for better presentation.
            Finally, the drink is topped with whole ice cubes and sparkling soda water.
            Mint leaves and lime wedges are used to garnish the glass.
        </comments>
        <ingredients>
            INGREDIENTS:
            4 cl (4 parts) White rum,
            3 cl (3 parts) Fresh lime juice,
            6 leaves of Mint,
            2 teaspoons Sugar,
            Soda Water.
        </ingredients>
        <mixing>
            MIXING:
            Mint sprigs muddled with sugar and lime juice.
            White rum added and topped with soda water.
            Garnished with sprig of mint leaves.
            Served with a straw.
        </mixing>
    </cocktail>
    <cocktail name="Cosmopolitan">
        <prime>vodka</prime>
        <description>
            A cosmopolitan, or informally a cosmo, is a cocktail made with vodka, triple sec, cranberry juice, and freshly squeezed or sweetened lime juice.
            The drink should be a frothy bright pink colour
            According to the International Bartenders Association the original recipe is based on vodka citron.
            The cosmopolitan is a relative of cranberry coolers like the Cape Codder.
            The Cosmopolitan gained popularity in the 1990s.
        </description>
        <history></history>
        <trivia>
            Cosmo was further popularized among young women by its frequent mention on the television program Sex and the City, where Sarah Jessica Parker's character, Carrie Bradshaw, commonly ordered the drink when out with her girlfriends.
            The film adaptation made a reference to its popularity when Miranda asks why they stopped drinking them, Carrie replies "because everyone else started."
        </trivia>
        <comments>
            sweet, fruity, juicy
            it is strong and its quite sweet
            First, always use Cointreau
            Second, the cranberry juice is mostly for color and just a little bit for taste.
            The Cosmopolitan should have a reddish hue!
            It should be translucent, not solid red in color.
            The best Cosmopolitans I've had have tiny ice crystals floating on top.
        </comments>
        <ingredients>
            INGREDIENTS:
            4 cl Vodka Citron,
            1.5 cl Cointreau,
            1.5 cl Fresh lime juice,
            3 cl Cranberry juice
        </ingredients>
        <mixing>
            MIXING:
            Add all ingredients into cocktail shaker filled with ice.
            Shake well and double strain into large cocktail glass.
            Garnish with lime wheel.
        </mixing>
    </cocktail>
    <cocktail name="Yorsh">
        <prime>beer, vodka</prime>
        <description>
            Yorsh is a Russian mixed drink consisting of beer thoroughly mixed with an ample quantity of vodka.
            It is traditionally drunk in a social setting, typically with a toast followed by downing a full glass of it at one go.
            Vodka is a neutral spirit which does not greatly alter the flavor of the beer, but does greatly increase its alcohol content.
            Yorsh is meant to be gulped down in one go, not sipped.
        </description>
        <history></history>
        <trivia>
            Russian Yorsh -- a blending of vodka and beer designed to make one's hair stand on end (in the name of the fish with protruding spines on its fins)
            In Russia, mixing vodka with anything else is considered a waste, unless the mixer is beer, which produces a fearsome beverage known as yorsh.
            Dedicated drinkers can prepare a fatal formula by mixing vodka and beer, this acquired-taste mix is called Yorsh and has been known to send 250 pound soldiers into a deep coma.
        </trivia>
        <comments></comments>
        <ingredients>
            INGREDIENTS:
            10 parts beer,
            1 part vodka (Ratio varies according to taste).
        </ingredients>
        <mixing>
            MIXING:
            Mix thoroughly and drink quickly.
        </mixing>
    </cocktail>
    <cocktail name="Screwdriver">
        <prime>vodka</prime>
        <description>
            A screwdriver is a popular alcoholic highball drink made with orange juice and vodka.
            While the basic drink is simply the two ingredients, there are many variations; the most common one is made with one part vodka, one part of any kind of orange soda, and one part of orange juice.
            Many of the variations have different names in different parts of the world.
            The International Bartender Association has designated this cocktail as an IBA Official Cocktail.
        </description>
        <history>
            This drink appears in literature as early as 1938 "And answered it "The famous Smirnoff Screwdriver", Just pour a jigger of smirnoff vodka over ice cubes, fill glass with orange juice and serve".
            Then later it is claimed that this drink was invented by American aviators "A Screwdriver — a half orange juice and half-vodka drink popularized by interned American aviators—costs a dollar including the customary barman's tip."
        </history>
        <trivia></trivia>
        <comments></comments>
        <ingredients>
            INGREDIENTS:
            5 cL (1 part) vodka,
            10 cL (2 parts) orange juice.
        </ingredients>
        <mixing>
            MIXING:
            Mix in a highball glass with ice.
            Garnish and serve.
        </mixing>
    </cocktail>
    <cocktail name="Bloody Mary">
        <prime>vodka</prime>
        <description>
            A Bloody Mary is a popular cocktail containing vodka, tomato juice, and combinations of other spices and flavorings including Worcestershire sauce, Tabasco sauce, piri piri sauce, beef consommé or bouillon, horseradish, celery, olives, salt, black pepper, cayenne pepper, lemon juice, and celery salt.
            It has been called "the world's most complex cocktail".
        </description>
        <history>
            The Bloody Mary's origin is unclear, and there are multiple conflicting claims of who invented the Bloody Mary.
            Fernand Petiot claimed to have invented the Bloody Mary in 1921, well before any of the later claims.
            He was working at the New York Bar in Paris at the time, which later became Harry's New York Bar
        </history>
        <trivia>
            The Bloody Mary is famed as a "hair of the dog" remedy (meaning that if you consume too much alcohol the night before, it's supposed to help assuage your pain the next morning).
            The name "Bloody Mary" is associated with a number of historical figures — particularly Queen Mary I of England, who was nicknamed as such in Foxe's Book of Martyrs for attempting to re-establish the Catholic Church in England — and fictional women from folklore.
            Some drink aficionados believe the inspiration for the name was Hollywood star Mary Pickford.
            Others trace the name to a waitress named Mary who worked at a Chicago bar called the Bucket of Blood.
            However, another argument for the origin of "Bloody Mary", that the name in English simply arose from "a failure to pronounce the Slav syllables of a drink called Vladimir" gains some credibility from the observation that the customer at Harry's Bar in Paris for whom Fernand Petiot prepared the drink in 1920 was Vladimir Smirnov, of the Smirnoff vodka family.
            A Bloody Mary is usually served on-the-rocks in an old-fashioned glass or in a tall (Collins) glass.
        </trivia>
        <comments>
            This Spicy Favorite Owns Sunday Morning
            This piquant mix of tomato juice and vodka is a forenoon favorite
            all that tomato juice gives you maximum beverage volume with minimal alcohol
            Plus, the drink holds its own against the assertive flavors of common brunch fare like bacon, sausage, and eggs.
            its taste is so robust that people rarely want more than one.
            You can spice it up or down to suit your own preference.
            Just so you can bask in their satisfied smiles as they sip your expert concoction.
            This is a drink that you want to experiment with, because everyone likes a different level of spiciness.
            Whatever secondary ingredients you use, feel free to experiment with measurements until you find a formula that suits your taste.
            Tabasco is a must, the spicier the better!
            It's refreshing and feels almost like a food.
            Very filling
            I love how versatile the drink really is
            They almost become a meal in and of themselves
        </comments>
        <ingredients>
            INGREDIENTS:
            4.5 cl (3 parts) Vodka,
            9 cl (6 parts) Tomato juice,
            1.5 cl (1 part) Lemon juice.
        </ingredients>
        <mixing>
            MIXING:
            Add dashes of Worcestershire Sauce, Tabasco, salt and pepper into highball glass, then pour all ingredients into highball with ice cubes.
            Stir gently.
            Garnish with celery stalk and lemon wedge (optional).
        </mixing>
    </cocktail>
    <cocktail name="White Russian">
        <prime>vodka</prime>
        <description>
            A White Russian is a sweet cocktail classically made with vodka, coffee liqueur (e.g., Kahlua or Tia Maria), and cream served with ice in an Old Fashioned glass.
            In modern times, many establishments have substituted milk for cream.
        </description>
        <history>
            The traditional cocktail known as a Black Russian, which first appeared in 1949, becomes a White Russian with the addition of cream.
            Neither drink is Russian in origin, but both are so named due to vodka being the primary ingredient.
            It is unclear which drink preceded the other.
        </history>
        <trivia>
            The White Russian is the signature drink of "the Dude", the protagonist of the cult classic The Big Lebowski.
            In the movie, the Dude refers to it as a "Caucasian."
            The cocktail's prominence in the film has been connected to a revival in its popularity.
        </trivia>
        <comments>
            Like liquid ice cream
            The key character in that movie — a slacker known as The Dude — drinks them often.
            With its mix of vodka, Kahlua, and sweet cream, the drink tastes like boozy ice cream.
            The Big Lebowski was written, produced, and directed by the Coen brothers — Joel and Ethan.
            The Dude (played by Jeff Bridges) is an unemployed slacker living in Los Angeles.
            Other than drinking White Russians, his chief interests are bowling and hanging out.
            The Dude refers to White Russian Cocktails as "Caucasians."
            "Careful, Man, There's a Beverage Here"
            "They bowl, too," said Mrs K R. "In fact, part of the event takes place in a bowling alley."
            I think I prefer the White Russian to them all because it is smooth and creamy and oh so delicious.
            Yes indeed, heavy in calories but oh so worth it!
            Drinkable desserts are fun-- and the boozy ones are a party in the mouth.
            It WAS like drinking melted ice cream --- what a terrific throw back recipe
            Vodka, Kahlua, and sweet cream and the drink tastes like boozy ice cream!
            this creamy, dreamy good cocktail is so delicious...
            They really were delicious milkshakes.
            This seems like a sweet tasty drink.
        </comments>
        <ingredients>
            INGREDIENTS:
            5 cl (5 parts) Vodka,
            2 cl (2 parts) Coffee liqueur,
            3 cl (3 parts) fresh cream.
        </ingredients>
        <mixing>
            MIXING:
            Pour coffee liqueur and vodka into an Old Fashioned glass filled with ice.
            Float fresh cream on top and stir slowly.
        </mixing>
    </cocktail>
    <cocktail name="Liquid nitrogen cocktail">
        <prime>liquid nitrogen</prime>
        <description>
            A liquid nitrogen cocktail is any mixed drink whose preparation involves the use of liquid nitrogen.
            Popularized as a novelty because of the smoky, bubbling "cauldron effect" it produces, liquid nitrogen is controversial as a cocktail ingredient because it boils at −196 °C (77 K; −321 °F) and its consumption is thus potentially lethal.
            Because of its low temperature liquid nitrogen can be extremely damaging to body tissue, causing frostbite and cryogenic burning on contact.
            If ingested it can lead to severe internal damage, destroying tissue in the mouth and digestive tract.
            Furthermore, as it evaporates liquid nitrogen releases a large volume of gas, which means it can burst the stomach if swallowed in a sufficiently large amount.
            However, it is not a regulated substance in most countries and there is little control of its use.
        </description>
        <history>
            The culinary use of liquid nitrogen is mentioned in an 1890 recipe book titled Fancy Ices authored by Mrs. Agnes Marshall, but has been employed in more recent times by restaurants in the preparation of frozen desserts, such as ice cream, which can be created within moments at the table because of the speed at which it cools food.
            Similarly, liquid nitrogen has become popular in the preparation of cocktails because it can be used to quickly chill glasses or freeze ingredients.
            It is also added to drinks to create a smoky effect, which occurs as tiny droplets of the liquid nitrogen come into contact with the surrounding air, condensing the vapour that is naturally present.
        </history>
        <trivia></trivia>
        <comments></comments>
        <ingredients>
            You don't wanna drink this.
        </ingredients>
        <mixing>
            Seriouly.
        </mixing>
    </cocktail>
    <cocktail name="Porn Star Martini">
        <prime>vodka</prime>
        <description>
            Pornstar Martini is a delightful mixture of vanilla vodka, Passoa, fresh passion fruit and vanilla syrup, and is served straight up with Prosecco.
            The sweet vanilla vodka flavours are balanced by the sharpness of the passion fruit and is complemented by a shot of prosecco which again gives a different experience of fizzy and dry.
        </description>
        <history>
            Another Ankrah original, and at first dubbed the Maverick Martini after a shady club in Capetown, South Africa, then renamed the Pornstar Martini, because of all the passion Ankhar would put into this drink.
            The idea is to eat the passion fruit first, then drink the Champagne and then enjoy the lavish Bols Passion Fruit Martini drink.
        </history>
        <trivia>
            Despite the name, the Pornstar Martini has become a firm favourite as a sophisticated drink amongst classy ladies.
            It tastes sweet, it's exotic, it comes in a nice glass and best of all it's served with a side of the nations favourite bubbly; prosecco.
            What's not to love?
            It's even rumoured that it was Ms. Kate Middleton's tipple of choice when she celebrated her hen party back in 2011.
            The drink is also a firm favourite down at London's Bar Soho, where punters can order a giant version of the cocktail to share between friends.
        </trivia>
        <comments>
            What needs to be said about this cocktail? First off, is that it is absolutely uh-mazing!
            Sweet, fruity and oh so over the top.
            A lot of people ask "what's with the shot of bubbles on the side".
            "That's the money Shot".
            it's actually the first sip that gets them truly hooked.
            Crisp, delicious, refreshing and undeniably classy, it's a drink that goes perfectly with any summer evening event or get-together..
            Served with a sparkler, extendable straws and passion fruit slices, it's no wonder it steals focus from all the other cocktails on the menu.
            The martini is a pretty sexy cocktail.
            Hell, even the glass it is served in is properly sensual.
            So how do you take one of the most erotic cocktails and turn the heat up even more?
            You turn it into a porn star, that's how.
            Our Pornstar Martini is classy, refined and just a little bit wild.
        </comments>
        <ingredients>
            INGREDIENTS:
            25ml Passion fruit flavoured vodka,
            25ml Vanilla flavoured vodka,
            50ml passion fruit puree,
            50ml orange juice,
            2 spoons caster sugar,
            0.5 a passion fruit to garnish,
            25ml Prosecco.
        </ingredients>
        <mixing>
            MIXING:
            Add vodka (both flavours), orange juice, passion fruit puree and the sugar to a cocktail shaker.
            Stir until sugar is dissolved.
            Add ice and shake vigorously for 7-10 seconds.
            Strain into a martini glass.
            Garnish with half a passion fruit and serve with a shot of prosecco.
        </mixing>
    </cocktail>
    <cocktail name="Corpse Reviver #2">
        <prime>gin</prime>
        <description>
            The Corpse Reviver family of cocktails are intended as 'hair of the dog' hangover cures, hence the name.
            Most of the corpse reviver cocktails have been lost to time, but the cognac and gin-based Corpse Reviver cocktails that were first listed in the Savoy Cocktail Handbook by Harry Craddock in 1930 have survived to this day.
        </description>
        <history>
            The corpse reviver appears in literature as early as an issue of Punch in 1861.
            An early recipe for the corpse reviver is found in literature as early as 1903.
        </history>
        <trivia>
            Harry Craddock: "Four of these taken in swift succession will unrevive the corpse again."
        </trivia>
        <comments>
            That's when some of those poor over-tippled souls desperately search for a remedy to soothe their aching beings.
            And an unfortunate few tipple way too much.
            Some swear by "hair of the dog" remedies.
            The idea is that drinking more booze can cancel out a hangover — or at least dull its pain.
            The "corpse-reviver" was one such class, so named because it could — figuratively speaking — bring a drinker back from the "dead."
        </comments>
        <ingredients>
            INGREDIENTS:
            3/4 oz gin (I suggest Plymouth's),
            3/4 oz Cointreau,
            3/4 oz Lillet Blanc (available in good liquor stores),
            3/4 oz lemon juice,
            1 or 2 drops of Pernod, Ricard, or absinthe - or any other pastis (anise-flavored liqueur),
            1 stemless cherry for garnish (optional).
        </ingredients>
        <mixing>
            MIXING:
            Stir with ice, strain into a chilled cocktail glass.
        </mixing>
    </cocktail>
</data>
